Liam Li 021-08829682

Full Stack Software Engineer

limeng0427@gmail.com

Summary

Certified AWS associate Solutions Architect, Developer.

Qualified and experienced full stack developer with local and overseas working experience. I am well-versed in developing web application, embedded system, web service from working experience and studying and I am experienced software development, debugging and testing. I have expertise in data structure, algorithms and data analysis which are also recognized by the former employers.

Skills

IT Skills Back-end Skills: .NET 4 MVC, .Net Core, C#, C, C++, Java, PHP, SQL Server,

Report/Email Service, RESTful Web Service/API, WCF, WinForms/WPF, LINQ, EF Front-end Skills: JavaScript(jQuery, Angular, TypeScript), HTML, CSS, Bower, Bootstrap Embedded System Skills: Assembly and Linux from work experience and studying

Test Skills: Unit Test, Manual and Automation Testing Skills, Selenium

Others: AWS, Data Mining and Machine Learning Skills including Weka and R

Project Skills Agile Development - Scrum, SDLC and Change Management, Source Control (Git, SVN)

Telecommunication Skills Telecommunications principle and different generations of technologies

Installation, maintenance and trouble-shooting of telecommunications equipment,

Customers Service Skills Empathy, patience and consistency; adaptability; sense of humor

Good English communication skills

Native Speaker of Mandarin

Education

Master of Science

Language Skills

Postgraduate Diploma July 2016 – July 2017 PGD in Computing

Department of Computing United Institute of Technology

Web Application Development, Agile & Lean Software Delivery, Network Programming,
Data Mining and Industry Applications, Machine Learning and Information Processing
September 2011 - July 2014
Control Theory & Control Engineering

School of Information Engineering Nanchang University

C++ Programming, Principles of GPS and Application, Computer Controlling System, Design of Embedded System, Sensor Technology & Application, Advanced Mathematics

Bachelor of Science September 2007 - July 2011 Automation

School of Information Engineering Nanchang University

C Language Programming, Data Structure, Electric Circuit, Smart Control Technology

PC principles and Port Technology (Assembly), Electronic and PLC control

Work Experience

Trackit Limited

April 2017 - May 2019

Software Developer

Auckland, New Zealand

Responsibilities: Developing new custom features (e.g. Logistic Tracking, Asset Service Maintenance), report service, database and web service with C#, JavaScript, SQL and Google Service. Releasing products and version management are also part of my weekly work. My job also includes supporting team members' technical queries and solutions.

Projects: GPS Tracking and Analyses Solution, Logistic Consignment Solution.

Technologies: C#, .Net 4, Generics, Winform/WPF, SQL Server, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, SVN, JIRA, Web Service, WCF, Report Service, WebPack, Exceptions Management, Asynchronous and multi-threaded applications.

◆ Ed.Collective January 2017 – March 2017 Database Developer, Contract

Auckland. New Zealand

Responsibilities: As the independent developer and data analyst of Ed.Collective data review project. I'm in charge of the technical design and working as SQL Server database developer to implement this project. I am pushing the data storage method shifting from Access to SQL Server along with data analyses project and making future working process more efficient to operate with standard coding and infrastructures including UDF, stored procedure and data import & process T-SQL script.

Projects: Ed.Collective Data Review Project; Ed.Collective Data Population Project **Technologies**: SQL Server, T-SQL, Stored Procedure, Dynamic SQL, SSMS, Data Analyses, Data Mining

◆ ZTE Global Telecommunication Corporation July 2014 – June 2015

Software Developer

Beijing, China

Responsibilities: Business Analyses for Automatic Switch Optical network software system; software development and unit test matching new features; system issues tracking and processing; development of command line code for site engineer; system debug with testers and developers from different sections of the system.

Projects: Wavelength Division Multiplexing Automatic Switch Optical Network for Intelligent OTN **Technologies**: Embedded System, C/C++ language, Java, Scrum Development, Unit Test, Integration Test

Nanchang UniversityJune2012 - May 2014

Project Manager

Nanchang, Jiangxi, China

Responsibilities: Software system design, development and testing; on site telecommunication cable and fiber wiring, fiber fusion, network environment build and configuration, plan and schedule making of project implementation; business analyses with information collected from factory manager; technical feasibility check; training courses delivery for new staffs or system users.

Projects: Silkworm Egg Incubation Monitoring System

Hospital miniature laboratory information management system (LIS)

Andon System for Automobile Workshop & Remote Energy Monitoring System

Lincomycin Fermentation Process Parameters Monitoring System

Manufacturing Information System (A4 Production Line)

Maintenance and Upgrade for Temperature Control System of Large Trolley Resistance Furnace

Technologies: SQL Server DB, Oracle DB, Java, .Net Framework, Delphi, Site Management, CRM, ERP

◆ BP Meadowbank

Customer Service, Part-time

May 2016 – September 2016

Auckland, New Zealand

Responsibilities: provide service to customers before, during and after a purchase.

◆ NZSales168 ICT Support

October 2015 - March 2016

Auckland, New Zealand

Responsibilities: equipment network problems shooting; ensure efficient use of applications and equipment; maintain websites; deal with daily sales affairs; communicate with customers to enquiry their requirement; do the training for new employees; check inventory; deal with customers' complains.

Interests

In my spare time, I volunteer in events and catch up friends by great walk, scuba diving, marathon, road trips.

Awards and Honors

- ◆ Awarded the Excellent Student Scholarship 5 times during undergraduate
- Awarded the second prize of college-level speech contest during undergraduate
- Awarded the first prize of university-level Mathematical Modeling Contest during undergraduate
- ◆ Obtained the title of university-level Excellent Student and Outstanding Student Leader during undergraduate

Reference

Available on request.

More detailed information can be found on LinkedIn: https://nz.linkedin.com/in/liamli2014